{"test_questions": [[{"question": "What are the two main applications for ac?", "opta": "direct, pulsating", "optb": "electric, magnetic", "optc": "power, information", "optd": "static, dynamic", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The distance that a signal's energy can travel in the time it takes for one cycle to occur is called the signal's:", "opta": "amplitude", "optb": "frequency", "optc": "wavelength", "optd": "period", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One oscilloscope selector knob that allows the major and minor divisions of the graticule to be used to determine a signal amplitude value is called the:", "opta": "time/cm control", "optb": "position control", "optc": "intensity control", "optd": "volts/cm control", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If current varies periodically from zero to a maximum, back to zero, and then repeats, the signal is:", "opta": "direct", "optb": "alternating", "optc": "pulsating", "optd": "repetitive", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What voltage will an ac voltmeter display?", "opta": "rms", "optb": "average", "optc": "peak", "optd": "peak-to-peak", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak value of a household appliance that uses a 230 V ac source?", "opta": "163 V", "optb": "230 V", "optc": "325 V", "optd": "480 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the waveform period difference between the 60 Hz electricity used in this country and the 50 Hz used in Europe?", "opta": "3 ms", "optb": "16 ms", "optc": "4 ms", "optd": "20 ms", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Test equipment selection enables the technician to both generate signals and:", "opta": "change circuit conditions", "optb": "inject signals", "optc": "sense circuit conditions", "optd": "change signal frequencies", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is ac current transfer more effective than dc current transfer over long distances?", "opta": "due to the height of power lines", "optb": "due to the use of ac generators", "optc": "due to step-up and step-down transformers reducing I2R losses", "optd": "due to very high voltages", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A sine wave reaches maximum positive voltage at:", "opta": "90\u00b0", "optb": "0\u00b0", "optc": "\u201390\u00b0", "optd": "360\u00b0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which percentages of full-amplitude rise time are used for a pulse wave?", "opta": "0 to 50 percent", "optb": "0 to 100 percent", "optc": "5 to 95 percent", "optd": "10 to 90 percent", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the average value of a 12 V peak wave?", "opta": "3.82 V", "optb": "4.24 V", "optc": "7.64 V", "optd": "9.42 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A test equipment item that has the ability to produce either square, triangular, or sawtooth waveforms is called:", "opta": "a function generator", "optb": "a radio frequency generator", "optc": "an audio frequency generator", "optd": "a frequency meter or counter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The current is flowing in what direction?", "opta": "clockwise", "optb": "counterclockwise", "optc": "in both directions at the same time", "optd": "50% of the time clockwise and 50% of the time counterclockwise", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the CRT oscilloscope display?", "opta": "voltage and period", "optb": "current and frequency", "optc": "rms voltage and current", "optd": "frequency and voltage", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power companies supply ac, not dc, because:", "opta": "it is easier to transmit ac", "optb": "there is no longer a need for dc", "optc": "dc is more dangerous", "optd": "there are not enough batteries", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a waveform period is determined to be 10 microseconds in duration, what is the frequency of the signal?", "opta": "100 Hz", "optb": "1000 Hz", "optc": "10 kHz", "optd": "100 kHz", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The phase difference between sine waves of different frequencies is:", "opta": "equal to their frequency differences", "optb": "the difference in their fixed time displacement", "optc": "the same throughout time", "optd": "constantly changing", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a sine wave signal is 100 mV peak-to-peak, how many volts would be measured by a voltmeter?", "opta": "14.14 mV", "optb": "35.4 mV", "optc": "63.7 mV", "optd": "70.7 mV", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What term expresses the frequency of a rectangular wave?", "opta": "Hz", "optb": "period", "optc": "PRF", "optd": "PRT", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "AC effective voltage is named:", "opta": "average", "optb": "peak", "optc": "peak-to-peak", "optd": "root mean square", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a voltmeter measures a sine wave as 500 mV, what would be its average value?", "opta": "159.0 mV", "optb": "318.5 mV", "optc": "353.5 mV", "optd": "451.0 mV", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Some AC Voltage Conversion: \n\nPeak to rms:     multiply peak by 0.707.\nPeak to average: multiply peak by 0.637.\nRms to peak:     multiply rms  by 1.414.\nRms to average:  multiply rms  by 0.9.\nAverage to rms:  multiply avg  by 1.111.\nAverage to peak: multiply avg  by 1.567.\n\nMostly voltmeter shows rms value. So, Vav = 0.9*Vrms \n = 0.9*500.\n = 450mV ~ [D] 451 mV."}, {"question": "One adjustable knob on the oscilloscope that allows the trace to be aligned with a reference graticule is called the:", "opta": "position control", "optb": "focus control", "optc": "intensity control", "optd": "volts/cm control", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Signal comparisons may be most easily seen when using which item of test equipment?", "opta": "spectrum analyzer", "optb": "multimeter", "optc": "function generator", "optd": "dual trace oscilloscope", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The magnitude that an alternation varies from zero is called its:", "opta": "altitude", "optb": "amplitude", "optc": "attitude", "optd": "polarity", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The power that is distributed from a power plant to your home is:", "opta": "high voltage to high voltage", "optb": "low voltage to high voltage", "optc": "high voltage to low voltage", "optd": "low voltage to low voltage", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A rectangular wave that has a duty cycle of 50 percent could be called a:", "opta": "c wave", "optb": "sawtooth wave", "optc": "square wave", "optd": "triangle wave", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A triangle wave consists of repeating:", "opta": "positive ramps only", "optb": "negative ramps only", "optc": "positive and negative ramps of equal value", "optd": "positive and negative ramps of unequal value", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the name of a device used to directly measure the frequency of a periodic wave?", "opta": "oscilloscope", "optb": "frequency meter or counter", "optc": "audio frequency generator", "optd": "radio frequency generator", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which control should be moved to display more cycles of a signal on an oscilloscope?", "opta": "horizontal position to left or right", "optb": "volts/cm to a smaller number", "optc": "vertical position to top or bottom", "optd": "time/cm to a higher setting", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the name of a device that converts sound waves to electrical waves?", "opta": "an amplifier", "optb": "an antenna", "optc": "a filter", "optd": "a microphone", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the frequency of a radio wave is increased, then its wavelength will:", "opta": "increase", "optb": "decrease", "optc": "remain the same", "optd": "cannot tell", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the rms voltage value of an ac signal whose peak oscilloscope display uses 3 major divisions above the zero setting? (V/cm = 5)", "opta": "5.3 V", "optb": "10.6 V", "optc": "15.0 V", "optd": "21.2 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak-to-peak current value when an ammeter measures a 20 mA value?", "opta": "14 mA", "optb": "28 mA", "optc": "40 mA", "optd": "57 mA", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How long would it take to transmit an electromagnetic wave to a receiving antenna 1,000 miles away?", "opta": "5.38 ms", "optb": "10.8 ms", "optc": "53.8 ms", "optd": "108 ms", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the waveform period of a square wave signal that horizontally covers 3 major divisions per cycle? (time/cm = 50 ms)", "opta": "50 ms", "optb": "100 ms", "optc": "150 ms", "optd": "200 ms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A sine wave has:", "opta": "four quadrants", "optb": "two alternations", "optc": "one period", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak-to peak voltage of a 56 Vrms ac voltage?", "opta": "158 V", "optb": "164 V", "optc": "82 V", "optd": "79 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One oscilloscope selector knob that allows the major and minor divisions of the graticule to be used to determine a waveform period is called a:", "opta": "focus control", "optb": "time/cm control", "optc": "intensity control", "optd": "volts/cm control", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the period of a 16 MHz sine wave?", "opta": "196 ns", "optb": "62.5 ns", "optc": "31.25 ns", "optd": "19.9 ns", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}